so anna we had three lessons so far so
you're really not a beginner but i got
asked a question
in one of my wall videos whether it's
good for a beginner to
start playing on the wall if they've
never played tennis before and i
actually have no idea if it's good or
not
i've never taken a beginner and put them
against the wall so today since you're
not really a beginner you already had
three lessons but you are a
wall beginner i want to see how you do
playing against the wall here hit a few
balls and let me see what's going on
okay
okay that's actually pretty good so
you're playing amazingly well on the
wall because you're very talented for
tennis
obviously but some other people might
have some trouble on the wall
and one of the most difficult things is
the actual feed so what you want to do
is
on the feet is very gently hit the ball
off the bounce so you bounce it to
yourself
hit it very gently and now as you start
to rally back and forth
to yourself you want to minimize the
take back so don't take the racket too
far back
and it's all about controlling the ball
you want to hit it very gently
and try to finish as much as you can you
see how i'm finishing
all the way across and i'm really not
taking the racquet back
very far as your confidence grows you
can start hitting it
harder and harder and eventually you can
hit on the wall
like this and completely rip the ball
but it will take some time alright give
it a shot
good minimize the take back
maximize the finish
do it again good and finish it all the
way
all right one thing on the wall that's
crucial is the foot works because the
ball
is not going to be super accurate coming
back to you so you have to move your
feet look if i hit it a little bit off
i got to move my feet and find the ball
right
i got to adjust to the ball that's going
all over the place so you don't want to
be
like stationary and planted you want to
stay on your toes and keep moving
all right here we go feet feet feet good
and finish it all the way
finish it all the way good
okay this is very normal see what
happens is a lot of times the ball will
start going high
and it turns into a real nightmare right
the ball goes hi look it goes high like
this
and now you have to play it high you're
backing up yeah so the best thing i
actually recommend is
once it starts going high you stop the
ball like don't try to rally this one
at this stage of your game there's no
point just if it goes high
like this just catch it and then start
over you really want to keep the ball
as low as possible good
and finish it nice nice
beautiful job nice and gentle
footwork
good job excellent
and get up get up get up nice look at
this rally
and again good
go nice okay so you're doing
predominantly four hands there and
that's actually a really good practice
getting out of the way hitting forehands
but you should also practice your
backhand and basically on the backhand
it's gonna be the same thing let me show
you a few okay
you have a two-handed backhand and you
want to minimize the take back and
maximize the finish you see
and just start very gently and it's
really the same
thing as the forehand small take back
and then a
full finish and then gradually if you're
feeling more confident you can start
increasing the pace and start hitting a
little bit harder
now you want to see a real hard one ah
there it is
nice small take back and finish all the
way good work
get up go go go
nice okay go a little deeper
it's much harder the backhand right yeah
but you should definitely practice it
you try one more i want to see you do a
five ball backhand rally you get five in
a row back and forth and by the way
if there's a forehand in between it
doesn't matter it's okay it doesn't have
to be all backhands but i want to see
five good backhands
one good back up two
all right see that one you would have
stopped anyway right the high one by the
way the main cause of the ball
shooting way up like that is an open
racket face so what happened there is
you
kind of going on the back foot the
racket opened up and the ball shot way
up so you want to avoid that but maybe
position yourself a little bit more
behind the ball as you're not falling
backwards
one two
three four one more
all right five i'll give it to you that
was in nice job all right
okay so as you get better with forehand
and backhand on the wall you can also
try to alternate so you can do one
forehand one backhand like this
forehand and then backhand
and forehand and backhand i'll give it a
try i want to see five good shots
one one
two
okay again you see when you fall back
when you get on that back leg the
racquet
opens up and it shoots way up so it's
footwork or if you feel like it's too
high for you like i told you before you
can just stop it and start over
i try it again one
one two
alternate alternate
all right try it again start over
another thing i forgot to mention on the
wall do you want to like play with dead
balls
if you bring brand new balls here
they're going to bounce too much and
it's going to be really hard to keep
them in place so
the dead are actually the better right
you're going to be able to
hit it harder and you're going to
control it much better okay all right
try it again
five balls alternating between forehand
and backhand
all right here we go one two good get
out of the way
three good four good
five keep going get out of the way go go
go all right you got five you got five
you got five good so what do you think
you like playing on the wall i love it i
think it's an effortless cardio
yeah it's really it has a golem it's a
really good cardio it's
actually really good for your tennis
it's good for your footwork and you can
pretty much work on any shot we're going
to not do serves and overheads today
but we're going to do volleys on the
wall and this is much more difficult
than the ground strokes i'm going to
show you how to do it you stand on this
side so you can see my racket basically
what you want to do
is open the racket face a little bit and
because you don't want to play the ball
too
low you end up hitting too many low
volleys so when you're violin against
the wall you want to put it a little bit
higher
and hit it very gently like this so you
get it nice and high and let's just let
the ball come off your strings like this
and control it now when you get more
comfortable with this movement
you start speeding it up and you start
hitting the ball a little bit lower
but you can see how calm my racket is
i'm basically just
deflecting the ball back in play like
that you want to try it
yeah it looks easy but i promise i
promise i promise you it's not as easy
as it looks
okay give it a try okay continental grip
and they make a nice soft high feed
go ahead yep okay remember we want to
put it higher if you hit it here
it's going to be impossible because the
ball is going to drop too low on you so
maybe here aim here and the way you get
it up look you just open the racket face
up like that
it's too low watch me i'm going to go go
against this wall watch my racket you
see how it's open
that sends the ball up that gives you
sufficient time to be able to get it
back and forth
if you get it low oh yes it's going to
cut the rally short
okay do it again play it high there you
go
now remember our valley lesson right you
want to keep the elbow in front
you don't want to turn too much and you
can also stand a little bit closer
but the elbow has to be in front of you
yes yes okay
okay the instinct that everyone has when
the ball arrives
but are you going to do it today i
promise you but the instinct everyone
has is
as soon as the ball comes people start
tucking and turning away from the ball
so what you got to do is just
hold your ground don't allow the ball
the ball to play you watch
watch i'm holding my ground see i'm not
letting that ball play me i'm not
going like this and i'm backing up i'm
holding my ground
and i'm just putting it nice and high
and going back and forth like that
okay try it out
one two three four
all right you got four in a row that's
pretty good should we try to go for ten
come on you can do it one
two three that's so stiff the arm look
at your arm is like completely locked
when you play the ball closer to you you
feel the ball more you feel it more when
you start extending the ball is further
away
you feel it a lot less so get the elbow
like close to your torso okay
one two three four
five come on six seven
eight nine ten yes
all right there you go the back and
valley is optional i recommend that you
leave this one alone but
in case i'm just gonna show you how to
do it in case the ball comes to your
back end that you're not doing this
windshield wiper stuff
that you were remember you were doing
that when we did our valley lesson
you're going like a windshield wiper
that's a bad habit so just in case you
got a backhand volley you're going to
hit it like this watch you can
look at it from here you're going to do
it remember you're using a two-handed
volley
and you're going to do the same thing
you'll play it in front and just put the
ball a little higher
and then just freeze the rack you see
how i'm freezing it here like that now
if you
feel like confident enough you can do it
with one hand as well
and this is actually really great on the
wall to build
the forearm stability you can build the
forearm and the hand muscles
so the forearm is more stable and then
you can alternate look forehand
backhand forehand backhand like that
two four five wow
six wow seven eight oh that was really
good
okay so i had no idea whether a beginner
can play on the wall but obviously
they can it's actually a pretty good way
to get started how was your experience
do you like it
i will be here i think you should it's
really good practice
we did like 10 15 minutes and you
already got a sweat going it's a great
workout all right good job i expect you
to come out here all the time okay
all right good job